Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-
Previously on
Star Trek: Strange New Worlds...
I read that the Aenar have
a form of precognitive ability.
I knew
you were going to ask that.
Hemmer may not be able to see.
but his other senses compensate.
You're keeping something
in the pattern buffer.
Rukiya. My daughter.
A year ago. she was diagnosed
with cygnokemia.
Story time?
You bet.
You've read this. like.
a hundred times.
That doesn't mean
that the ending
couldn't miraculously change.
Chief medical officer's
personal log.
Stardate 2341.6.
The Enterprise is conducting
a routine survey
of the Jonisian Nebula.
There isn't a great deal
for sickbay to do.
so I've been continuing
my own research.
The patient's condition
has not improved.
Months have become days
and have become hours.
Every minute
has become invaluable.
She has so little time left.
Daddy.
finish the story.
I like it
when you read the ending.
You need to go back in. Rukiya.
Just finish it with me.
Please?
"King Ridley
"scanned the battlefield
as Queen Neve's forces
"approached the border
of his kingdom.
"Things were dark.
"The king's chamberlain.
"Sir Rauth.
had turned against them.
"Their only ally...
"...Princess Thalia.
"had fallen to the evil queen.
"And now King Ridley
- was gravely outnumbered and..."
- I hate this part.
But you wanted me
to read it to you.
I know.
It's just I always wish
the Huntress
would come along and help.
You know.
like get together with Sir Adya
- and rescue the king.
- But that's not what happens.
King Ridley is forced to choose.
- Give up his greatest weapon...
- The Mercury Stone.
...or rescue Princess Thalia.
I know.
But what if we could change
the ending?
Someday.
when you're a grown-up.
you'll write your own stories.
And you can have
any ending you like.
But I have to
get better first. right?
Yes.
When I'm better.
can I see your quarters?
I'll take you to see
the whole ship.
I love you. Daddy.
I love you. too.
Always.
Good night.
♪
Chemical 3-QND contained.
Doctor. the shuttle crew
landed several hours ago.
Is there a reason
they haven't been
cleared for active duty yet?
I'm sorry.
I must have gotten
a little lost in my research.
I'll get right to it.
Are you getting any closer?
No.
The last thing I tried
literally blew up in my face.
Maybe you're
pushing yourself too hard.
Rukiya has been living
in that transporter
for too long.
Much longer than I anticipated.
And even so.
her time is now running out.
There has to be a cure.
I just need to find it.
I sympathize
with your duties as a father.
But I also have to remind you
of your duties
as our chief medical officer.
Understood. Commander.
I will ensure
that the landing party
is cleared for duty immediately.
But first.
why don't you get some rest.
You can see to the landing party
- when you're feeling better.
- I'm fine.
Take it as an order then. Doctor.
The crew isn't going anywhere.
And neither is Rukiya.
Thank you. Una.
Cadet Uhura informs me
that all data buoys
have been retrieved.
And with that.
our survey of the nebula
appears to be complete.
I could get used to this.
Sir?
This.
No battles. No chaos.
Just scanning a nebula
and focusing on the science.
Nice change of pace.
wouldn't you agree?
Captain. you have
repeatedly told me
that humans have a superstition
against calling attention
to good things
by saying them out loud.
Why. Mr. Spock.
I never took you
for the superstitious type.
Hmm. Erica.
set a course
for McNair Starbase.
Drinks are on me.
Course set
and ready for warp
on your mark. sir.
You gonna say the thing?
Hit it.
I said "hit it."
I'm hitting it. Captain. but...
we're not moving.
Mitchell. what's going on
with my ship?
All systems
are in the green. sir.
but we're frozen in place.
- Mr. Spock?
- Scans indicate
a minor synchrotron flux
emanating from
inside the nebula.
Perhaps that has affected
our warp capabilities.
Or...
Or?
Perhaps you did.
indeed. jinx it.
Let's hope that's all we have
to worry about. Mr. Spock.
Pike to Engineering.
We still got a warp core
down there?
Despite our lack of motion.
the warp core
seems to be functioning
within normal parameters.
Perhaps the nebula
has merely affected
our ability to achieve
a static warp bubble.
Suggest we engage
impulse thrusters
until we are clear
of its gravitational influence.
I concur with Mr. Spock's plan.
Great. Let's do it.
Transferring power to impulse.
Ortegas? Get us out of here.
Kissing this nebula goodbye.
take two.
Bridge to Dr. M'Benga.
Emergency.
Lieutenant Ortegas is injured.
On my way. Captain.
Bridge.
- Hi.
- Move!
All hail the king!
The king.
What the hell?
Space.
The final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its five-year mission:
to explore strange new worlds...
...to seek out new life
and new civilizations.
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
♪
I came to see Ortegas. but...
Ortegas...?
I...
You mean Sir Adya. Come. come.
Sir Adya?
From the book?
The book. sire?
Is this some
kind of a joke. Captain?
If it is jokes you desire.
I could summon the court jester.
- Summon the court jest...
- No.
Hold the jester!
It's just...
You're all dressed up
like characters
from the book
I've been reading to my...
Well. Ortegas is Sir Adya.
And you are clearly
Sir Amand Rauth?
Your loyal chamberlain.
Was this your idea?
My idea to... what. sire?
Mm. perhaps it would be best
if you took a seat. King Ridley.
Maybe I should sit.
Perhaps
Your Highness is parched.
A sip of wine would refresh you.
What are you doing?
I'm just trying to help
our poor. tired king.
Where did the wine
come from. Rauth?
Let's see.
It came from beside the carafe.
It is my sworn duty
to tend
to the king's well-being.
He shall drink nothing
I have not tasted first.
And as chamberlain.
the king's health
is my greatest concern.
Your words could polish
the finest of apples. Sir Rauth.
Perhaps they are
better suited...
Ow.
...to the kitchen.
I need a moment. Computer.
are you registering any
abnormal readings on the bridge?
- "Computer"?
- He obviously means
The Oracle.
Computer?
The explosion.
Perhaps the 3-QND
is causing me to hallucinate.
- I need to get to sickbay.
- To sickbay.
Uh. sorry. Your Highness.
Where is this bay?
And. ooh. do I need
to commandeer a ship?
I knew
this dreadful fog was a bad omen
as soon as it appeared.
Fog?
What fog?
A mysterious smoky wall.
It has engulfed
the entire kingdom. sire.
Poisonous air.
I wager it's a curse
sent by Queen Neve.
Sorcery is a coward's weapon.
Give me a clean kill
by sword any day.
Really?
- Uh...
- Where are you going?
- Sire?
- I'm going to get a medical...
A magical device.
Called a tricorder.
It will give me some answers.
Just stay here.
Both of you.
- My king.
- My liege.
It is wonderful to see you.
King Ridley.
What brings you to my sanctuary?
I'm looking for this.
Some sort of...
healing stone?
Its readings indicate
I'm perfectly healthy.
Readings?
Allow me to examine you.
So much pain.
It weighs down your spirit.
You should have
come to me sooner.
And what does your device
say of me?
- It seems your dopamine levels are highly elevated.
- Dopamine?
My king.
I know you said not to follow.
but Princess Thalia insisted.
My dear.
brave King Ridley.
I'm so grateful
to have finally found you.
Queen Neve
has invaded my kingdom.
She's obsessed
with the Mercury Stone.
She thinks I have it.
Her Crimson Guard
captured my throne
and imprisoned my subjects.
I mean. I scarcely escaped
with my life.
not to mention
my poor little Runa.
- Isn't that right?
- That. uh...
- Mommy loves you so much.
- That is terrible.
I know
you have the Mercury Stone
safely in your keeping.
I...
Sure.
Yes.
The stone is safe.
Heed me.
If you do not harness
the stone's powers
to capture and stop Queen Neve.
she will have all of us
in chains.
Your kingdom
will fall as mine has.
Uh. what is this?
This does not look
like the Mercury Stone.
You are very perceptive.
It is not.
Oh!
You have another weapon
in your mighty arsenal.
Oh! Brutal Queen Neve stands
nary a chance. Runa. does she?
My Princess Runa applauds you.
What are her dopamine levels?
Also higher than normal.
Is that bad?
Is it good?
It's curious.
It's a sign of heightened
neurological activity.
My king. the princess is right.
If you're not prepared to use
the power of the stone.
then allow me to lead an attack
against the Crimson Guard.
Their heads will roll.
Perhaps we could refrain from
any unnecessary head chopping.
Oh. That's disappointing.
Lieutenant Mitchell. take your hands
off me.
I'm your superior officer.
The Crimson Guard.
Let me go.
I'll have you court-martialed.
Silence.
Did you think your crimes
would go unpunished. wizard?
I'm not a wizard.
- I'm the chief engineer.
- You wear a wizard's robes.
This is absurd. I don't know
where these came from.
They just appeared.
Proof of your powers. wizard.
Halt your dark deeds.
accursed Crimson Guard!
Your hour of cruelty
is at an end.
for King Ridley is here
to strike fear
in your evil hearts.
Um...
Uh. release
Caster the Wizard at once.
We don't answer to you.
false king.
Unless you're here
to surrender the Mercury Stone.
But what about
the Letter of Accords?
Are not Lady Audrey's woods
neutral territory
by royal agreement?
You have no rights here.
The king speaks the truth.
Queen Neve
no longer acknowledges
the Letter of Accords.
These are now her woods.
and it won't be long
before your kingdom
is hers. too.
- Hemmer.
- Dr. M'Benga.
please. help me. Everyone else
has lost their minds.
My king. perhaps it is time
to unleash the stone's power.
I... don't actually
have the stone.
- What?
- But I know who might.
That wizard. Caster?
He knows where it is.
We must rescue him.
Absolutely. Good plan.
Fantastic.
Queen Neve will be keeping
Wizard Caster here
in the deepest part
of her dungeon
at the center of her realm
surrounded
by her most powerful forces
and weapons.
My good king. you mustn't go.
You will surely fall victim
to her most terrible magics.
The princess is shrewd.
as always.
Staging a rescue
would be unwise.
Diplomacy might be more prudent.
I'm sorry.
but we need the Mercury Stone.
And it's hard to hear
- over the sound of your trembling boots.
- That's enough.
We're going to try diplomacy.
If that doesn't work. then
you can cut something in half.
Thank you. sire.
Starfall is thirsty.
Ridiculous name for a sword.
- You're ridiculous.
- You are both
going to escort me
to Queen Neve.
With as little bickering
as possible. please.
And what of me. my Lord?
And Runa?
She should stay here.
And. um. you should stay
to protect her.
Oh. a wise plan.
my king.
We shall await your return.
And if you should fall
in battle.
I will sing...
...an epic song...
♪ Of mourning.♪
Great.
Okay.
Let's go.
I think I might
be more useful staying...
- Oh. man!
- All right.
This forest is full
of Crimson banners.
Queen Neve grows more brazen
by the day.
We are not alone.
Step forward.
Slowly.
Please point that elsewhere.
Pollux the Wizard?
King Ridley.
I'm surprised to find you here.
though I cannot say
if I think it foolish or brave.
Right.
Well. we're looking
for the Wizard Caster.
Ah. A fool's errand. then.
for he is now in the hands
of Queen Neve.
And what is to keep us
from simply marching in there
and taking him?
The Swamp of Infinite Deaths.
- Oh. that is not a good swamp.
- Alas.
the only way to her kingdom
takes you straight through it.
Oh. Oh. turn back then?
- Yes? No?
- I would die infinite deaths
to no longer hear your whining.
Are you sure. Pollux.
that there is no way
for you to help us?
- Why should I help you?
- Because
Caster is your brother?
- He is?
- I had no idea.
How did you know?
I read it in a book.
And you would... help Caster?
Not merely use him
for his power?
If you lead us
through the swamp.
I promise to free him.
Hmm.
I shall aid you. then.
There is a way around the swamp.
A secret way.
A dark way.
Follow me.
Queen Neve has my brother Caster
in her dungeons.
This tunnel
should lead us there.
Are you sure we can trust him?
No.
I'm sure we can't trust him.
But that's okay.
This is still the only way
to get to Caster.
If you say so. sire.
Welcome to my kingdom.
Now kneel before me.
Yes. of course.
My king. we have been led
into a trap.
I suspected as much.
You knew?
Loosely.
In any case. I knew
Queen Neve should be entering
the story right about now.
And I knew I should have
stayed in the castle.
It's always safer at home. Ow.
Welcome. King Ridley.
Now. where is the Mercury Stone?
Could be anywhere. really.
Fine.
I'll let my torturers drag
its location out of you. then.
They love their work.
They're very... thorough.
They look everywhere.
I promise you'll be compensated
well for your loyalty. sorcerer.
Thank you. Queen Neve.
You wanted to see my brother?
Now you can join him.
In the dungeon.
I can't take it anymore.
I tell you!
The walls!
The walls are starting
to close in on me!
Hemmer. am I glad to see you.
Are we the only two crew members
who are unaffected?
- It would appear so.
- Do you have
any idea why everyone's
acting so strangely?
They're all playing characters
from a children's book
- called The Elysian Kingdom.
- A children's book?
- How do you know this?
- Because I read it to my daughter.
It's a long story.
The important question to ask
is why you and I aren't affected
and why they are.
I thought
the important question is
where is the Mercury Stone?
- Stone?
- It's a weapon.
But it's fictional.
From the book.
- Where is this weapon?
- Well. in the book. Caster
helps King Ridley to find it.
- I have no idea how to find it.
- I know. I came to rescue you
because you're the only
other person unaffected.
which means you can help
solve the real problem.
How do we undo all of this?
Where were you when it started?
In Engineering.
I had just checked
the warp engines.
and I suddenly felt...
I don't know.
a consciousness
press against my own.
Luckily. my years
of telepathic training
allowed me to block it.
Consciousness?
Coming from where?
I didn't have time
to figure it out.
I assume I'm able
to keep my memories
because
of my telepathic abilities.
Have you considered. Doctor.
the entity I sensed
might have pulled the story
from your mind?
But why?
Impossible to know
without asking.
Hemmer.
do you think
you can make contact
with this entity again?
Contact with it is unpleasant.
That's why I blocked it.
It felt as if my brain were
being squeezed through my nose.
I did that to a man once.
I was. however.
able to sense that the entity's
not on another ship
but rather a part
of the nebula itself.
Do you think if we access
the ship's scanner array.
we can learn more
about this entity?
It's quite possible.
Engineering is close by.
I can control
the ship's systems from there.
We have to find a way out
of here first.
And fast.
Maybe I can get us out of here
with the help
of some powerful magic
called science.
What would a human magician say?
Abracadabra.
Abracadabra. I like it.
Don't look. It'll blind you.
What about you?
I am a wizard.
Oh. thank goodness.
Oh!
Not bad. wizard.
I like this...
science.
What do you mean
that the prisoners have escaped?
The wizard conjured
his way out of the cell.
And yet you stand here cowering
- instead of going after them.
- I was
- about to.
- You were about to?
You were
about to lose your head.
Be grateful your queen
is feeling merciful today.
I will give you another chance
to earn my favor.
Pollux.
would you be so kind
as to take my Crimson Guard
and bring back my prisoners
before I toss you in the dungeon
in their place?
As you wish. my liege.
Once inside.
I can block the door.
That should give us time to
access the ship's scanner array.
And what ship. pray tell.
are you speaking of?
Spock.
Pollux.
Get out of our way.
Or what?
You're unarmed.
I have armed myself.
It would seem Adya has
this fight well under control.
Perhaps I would serve you best
from the safety of the castle.
- Sure.
- Thank you. sire!
Really?
Sir Rauth isn't exactly known
for his bravery.
This isn't over.
Yes. it is.
What's happening? Who is this?
Z'ymira the Huntress.
She's an ally.
Z'ymira.
Adya.
You said you would call on me.
- Been a busy time.
- A raven
would be too much trouble?
Can we not do this now?
I saved your life.
That's something. right?
As grateful as I am
for whatever this is.
but we really should be
hurrying on to Engineering.
Yes. We should put an end
to this fantasy
before someone
seriously gets hurt.
This is most unusual.
When I scan the nebula. I find
evidence of a single life form.
including brain activity.
and yet
there is no sign
of a physical body.
A consciousness without a body.
Floating in space.
With the power to create
a new reality?
Sounds almost like
you're describing a god.
Doctor. are you familiar
with the theory
of the Boltzmann brain?
I recall learning something
about it in university.
A Boltzmann brain
is a theoretical. spontaneously
generated consciousness.
It may be we have
just encountered one.
So one day...
out of nothing.
an all-powerful being just...
appears?
And this consciousness
has somehow trapped
our ship in the nebula?
And turned the crew
into the characters
from a book I've read?
At least it made you the hero.
Let's say you're right.
How do we get it to stop?
Because until we do.
we are stuck here.
Perhaps you are the problem.
It's recreating
a story you read.
It is possible the entity
is reading your brainwaves.
If we can find a way
to sever that connection.
like by hurting you.
the entity might let
the Enterprise go.
You dare to threaten my king?
Stand down. Adya.
I can shoot him with an arrow
if that helps.
I don't really understand
what's going on.
I thought the point
was to hurt the king.
What's wrong with you?
I have sworn an oath
to protect him.
You'll just never
understand that. will you?
I am Huntress of the Forest.
I swore my allegiance
to no one but her.
You know that.
Sometimes I wonder
if we have anything
- in common.
- Perhaps it is
your differences
which drew you together.
Hold on a second.
Something's wrong here.
Your Majesty?
This is not how the story goes.
The two of you...
Adya. Z'ymira...
you don't even know each other.
Not to contradict you.
but we know each other quite.
quite well.
Quite well.
But you're not supposed to.
The two of you
never actually meet
in the book.
Except... Rukiya.
Rukiya? Is she a character?
She's my daughter.
She has always hated
how the story ended.
She wanted Sir Adya
and Z'ymira to team up.
I told her
when she grew up she could
become a writer and give herself
the ending she wanted.
Are you suggesting...
the entity did not take
the story from you.
but rather from your daughter?
Where is Rukiya?
She's gone.
She was beamed out of the buffer
at 08:45 hours this morning.
To... somewhere on the ship.
But it won't give me
her exact location.
That's very odd.
Hemmer...
my daughter is very sick.
The longer she stays
out of the buffer.
the faster her illness
will progress.
- She's dying.
- I'm so sorry. Doctor.
Let me help.
We have to find her.
I'm starting
to think she might be
the only one who can put
an end to all this.
The Mercury Stone is a girl?
If this is true...
I shall take her from him.
And make her my own.
How will you do that. my liege?
No. No. no. no. no.
Unhand me. you brute. Ow.
No. no. no. no. no. no.
I'm too young to die.
Oh!
Please.
I beg you... spare me.
Whether you live or die
depends entirely on you.
Sir Rauth.
What do you want from me?
Your loyalty.
Oh.
The forest calls.
Damn it!
Doctor?
I take it you've had
no luck finding her.
No.
I have not.
Someone...
...something...
took her out of the buffer
and hid her.
Perhaps we are thinking of this
the wrong way.
Where would your daughter
want to go?
My quarters are down here.
Rukiya always said
she wanted to see them.
Your Majesty. I am so glad
to see you alive and safe.
No thanks to your cowardice.
I lament.
I am not a fighter.
But what purpose would
my death have served.
if it merely led
to King Ridley's downfall?
You would worm your way
out of anything. wouldn't you?
Please... now is not
the time to fight.
We need to get into my quarters
right away.
Open.
I am sorry. my liege.
Did you really think
I was going to let you destroy
everything I've worked for.
King Ridley?
I should have known
you would betray us. Rauth.
Truthfully. I should have
known it as well...
...since that's what
he does in the book.
Don't beat yourself up about it.
I am sorry. Your Majesty.
But she promised me
your kingdom and...
who could turn that down?
All right.
As you were not willing to bend
to my will.
I found someone who would.
Give up. dear brother.
Your powers are
no match for mine.
There is no reason
you have to die.
Pollux is right.
All I want
is King Ridley's secret weapon.
This so-called...
Mercury Stone.
The girl in his quarters.
Let us have her. and I'll
let you and Caster live.
You shall not touch my daughter.
Or I will bring the might
of my kingdom
down upon your heads.
He's right. Queen Neve.
Turn away now.
or I'll unleash the full power
of my powerful wizard...
...powers.
I'll... I'll... I'll...
send you to the Event Horizon.
A dark realm
full of chaos and monsters
and...
There is no such place.
My Queen. He's bluffing.
What are you doing?
Abra...
cadabra!
Nice wizard powers.
I found this in Sickbay.
I set it to trigger
the transporter.
They're in Cargo Bay 12.
Once again. the magic
of science prevails.
Too much?
I know.
Sir Adya. guard my quarters.
With my life. Sire.
Daddy. you made it!
There's no trace of cygnokemia.
You're healthy.
How?
My friend made me better.
Your friend?
She woke me up.
and we've been playing.
I could see you. Daddy.
You did such a good job.
Did you have fun?
I did.
But it's time to stop playing.
Can we put everything back
the way it was?
Why? My friend said we could
play as long as I want.
Your friend doesn't mean to.
but she's hurting my friends.
They need to return
to their lives.
Do I have to go back
into the buffer. Daddy?
I don't know.
Frankly. I don't understand
what's happening.
Rukiya.
Can I talk to your friend?
It doesn't really work that way.
Perhaps...
I can be of some assistance.
You said if you tried to connect
to the consciousness again.
it could kill you.
I know. but...
maybe if Rukiya told
her friend we need to talk.
the entity might be
more inclined to cooperate.
They'd like to talk to you
if that's okay.
If you would like.
you may speak through me.
Please be gentle.
You must not take the child.
We don't mean you any harm.
But I need you
to stop this fantasy.
You're putting
my crew in danger.
The needs of your crew
are inconsequential.
You must protect the child.
You have an attachment
to Rukiya.
We are alike.
She was lonely.
Like me.
Lonely?
How did you know?
When I probed your ship.
I felt her imprisoned
in your machine.
I sensed her loneliness.
It matched my own.
I created this world for her.
To give her
a piece of her childhood
you didn't allow.
I was trying to protect her.
Everything I did was
to keep my daughter alive.
I was looking for a cure.
But I'm all better now. Daddy.
And I thank you for that.
But whatever you are doing
to create this fantasy.
the crew cannot live like this.
You have to let them go.
If I leave.
the child will die.
My being near her cures her.
If I release the ship
and the child goes with you.
she will grow sick again.
The ship cannot stay here.
Then you must make a choice.
The crew or your daughter.
You can't ask me to do that.
I had fun out here.
But I'll go back into the buffer
if you want me to. Daddy.
There must be another way.
There is.
You could leave
and she could stay.
How would she live?
It is her body that is ill.
But her consciousness
could join with me.
She would be free of sickness.
She will never know death.
Daddy?
Your friend.
She wants you to go with her.
Can you come. too. Daddy?
You know how in the story
King Ridley has
the Mercury Stone?
He wants to keep it.
It protects him.
Makes him happy.
Until he learns
that it has a soul.
And that it will die
if he holds onto it.
He has to let it go.
Even though it means
he won't be happy anymore.
You're my Mercury Stone.
Remember I told you you could
write your own stories someday?
Maybe that someday is now.
But it's up to you.
I want to.
Okay. brave girl.
I love you. Daddy.
I love you. too. baby.
Always.
It tickles. Daddy.
Rukiya?
Hello. Daddy.
Thank you.
For everything.
You were right... I've been
creating my own adventures.
I wish I could tell you
what I've seen.
Seen?
You just left.
Moments for you have been
years for me and Debra.
Debra.
You named the entity after...
Mom.
Oh.
Oh...
You look...
so much like her.
Do I?
I'm happy.
I'm safe.
You did the right thing.
Someday we'll see
each other again.
I know we will. but...
you have to live
your own life now.
Create your own stories.
Promise me you'll be happy.
I promise.
I have the worst headache.
Doctor...
am I in your quarters?
You don't remember?
The last thing I recall...
...is becoming stuck
in the Jonisian Nebula.
Chief medical officer's
personal log. supplemental.
None of the crew
remember what happened.
The entity's doing.
My daughter's doing.
I'm sure.
The surveillance logs are blank.
It's as if every one of them
lost five hours.
Except for me.
Joseph?
Rukiya?
She's fine.
She's alive.
She's safe.
But. Una.
I have been through something...
extraordinary.
And no one on the ship remembers.
You know what happened
in the missing five hours.
Sounds like a hell of a story.
It is.
It begins...
like all good stories.
Once upon a time.
Captioning sponsored by CBS
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm